So here I have set up a grid that now is using six boxes,
这里我们有一个由 6 个 box 组成的 grid
which we can see spread out across here.
也就是这里展开的这些元素
But as we see they are spread out in this funny way where it looks like
不过我们可以看到现在的样式看着比较奇怪
the first box and the second box have plenty of room.
第一个 box 和第二个 box 占据了很大的空间
Then we start squishing these boxes in here.
剩余的 box 则开始压缩了
To understand this behavior,
为了弄清楚这个行为
we can look at the code.
我们需要看看我们的代码
Here in grid-template-rows, I've set the first row to be 350 pixels.
在 grid-template-rows 中 我设置了第一行为 350 像素
The second row to be 350 pixels.
第二行也是 350 像素
Then the third row, I'm using 1fr.
然后第三行这里 我设置了 1fr
It denotes taking up the rest of the available space.
它会占据剩余可用的空间
So the available space is figured out by taking
剩余的可用的空间是容器的高度
the height of your container which I've set to a 100 view port height,
这里也就是 100vh 的高度
subtracting from it the space you've already used which would
减去前两个行已经占据的空间
be anything in a row and the grid gap.
以及它们之间的间隙距离
Then 1fr is leaving room for anything else.
剩余的空间就属于 1fr 了
So after we've taken up all of our 350 pixels, our 350 pixels,
我们减去这里的 350 像素 这里的 350 像素
and our grid gap twice at 15px,
两个 15 像素的间隙
it smushes the rest of it into our last row,
剩余的就全部分配给它
which is why we can see here it starts to smush at the bottom.
也就是为什么我们会看见底部会被压缩了
But 1fr can not be used more than once.
我们也可以多次使用 1fr 单位
I could split it up and I could say I want it to be 350 pixels,
比如 这里我们分配一个 350 像素
350 pixels, and then twice to go through and split up the space evenly.
另一个 350 像素 然后将剩余空间平均分配成 2 份
Now it would look like this.
它就变成这样了
But get this, we don't need to use pixels at all.
我们也可以根本就不使用像素单位
Here I'm setting up columns,
这里我设置了一些列
seven columns that each use 1fr: 1,2,3,4,5,6,7.
7 个列 都设置为 1fr
I'm going to take away the seventh because now we only have six elements.
因为这里我们只有 6 个元素 所以我们删掉一个
But this is saying to divide up evenly 1fr for each of them, the columns.
这里的意思是每个元素按照 1：1 的比例均匀分配所有空间
So here we can see now we have six equal columns coming across our boxes.
所以这里我们可以看到有 6 个等分的列
Let's make the background a little darker to make it easier to see.
我们把背景颜色调暗一些 这样可以看得更清晰一些
My favorite hex value in the world, 444.
我最喜欢的颜色值是 444
We'll make the color,
再设置一下文字颜色
this is from Edward Tufte's suggestion of fffff8;
来自 Edward Tufte 的建议 #fffff8
which is slightly off white.
稍微淡一点点的白色
Let's make it a little easier to see with a bigger font size.
同时也把字体大小设置得更大一些
Now we can see our columns spread evenly.
好了 现在可以很清楚的看见等分的列了
But, let's be honest,
但是 老实说
going through and writing 1fr six times is a lot of work.
重复写 6 次 1fr 比较麻烦
Programming is supposed to automate a lot of our work for us.
编程就是要让代码自动帮我们做一些事情
This is where the repeat function comes in.
这就是为什么会有一个 repeat 函数
These two lines of code do the exact same thing.
这两行的代码拥有一样的效果
I'll prove it to you. Let's comment out this and we'll leave our repeat function.
真的 我们把这行代码注释掉 然后换成 repeat 函数的方式
It's seven when we want it to be six remember.
然后我们设置为重复 6 次
Now we have six boxes spread out evenly by using repeat.
现在六个盒子就是平均分配的状态了
Repeat, it takes the number of times we want it to repeat
repeat 函数接受一个数字 也就是我们要重复的次数
which is six for us because we have six elements and then the size.
这里就是 6 然后另外一个参数是尺寸
So I'm saying repeat 1fr which means the rest of the available space six times.
所以设置为 1fr 意思就是将剩余的空间平均分配成 6 份
I could also use repeat with pixels,
我们也可以使用像素单位
25 pixels is pretty small.
25 像素有点小
But you can see I've repeated six times the column.
但是你可以看见它重复生成了 6 列
Let's do something that looks a tiny bit less bizarre.
让我们来做一些不那么奇怪的事情
So by using repeat,
通过使用 repeat 函数
we can automate the creation of our grid-template-columns.
我们可以自动生成 grid-template-columns 值
Now, let's talk about rows.
现在我们再来看看行属性
If you think about it when you're doing web development,
如果你做 web 开发的话
there's oftentimes where you're going to want
有时候你可能会想要
an infinite number of rows or as many rows as there is content.
实现一个无限行的列表 根据具体的内容来生成
Think about the way a Facebook feed works.
类似 facebook 中的 feed 一样
You just continue to go down and down and down.
你可以不断的往下滑动
So it's not like you're setting the number of rows initially,
所以你不可能在一开始就设置好固定的行数
the number of rows need to develop from the amount of content you have.
总的行数应该根据内容的具体情况来生成
Luckily for us, CSS grid makes this fairly easy with the grid-auto-rows syntax.
幸运的是 CSS grid 允许你通过 grid-auto-rows 语法来轻易的实现它
Grid-auto-rows replaces grid-template-rows. In this instance,
在这里可以使用 grid-auto-rows 来替换掉 grid-template-rows
we're going to use grid-auto-rows with minmax.
然后使用 minmax 设置参数
Now minmax works similarly to repeat.
minmax 和 repeat 函数类似
Repeat took two values,
repeat 函数接受 2 个值
minmax takes two values.
minmax 也接受 2 个值
The first is a minimum value that each row must be.
第一个值是每行所占的最小空间
So this is saying that each row has to be at least 100 pixels and at most is auto.
所以这里意思是每行至少占用 100 像素的空间 最大设置为 auto
So what auto will do is auto will let it be as big as its content holds.
auto 的意思是它可以尽可能的占据所需的空间
So if we have giant letters,
所以如果我们有一个很大的文字
then it'll be a much taller row.
它可以显示得非常高
But they have to be at least 100 pixels.
但是最低得有 100 像素
Let's take a look at what this looks like in our code.
我们在代码中来看看
So here we can see now that we have very very evenly made rows just by using minmax.
这里我们可以看到所有的行都非常均匀的分布在容器中
So now let's try to put together the grid-auto-rows using
让我们来使用 minmax 设置 grid-auto-rows 属性
minmax and grid-template-columns using 1fr.
同时设置 grid-template-columns 为 1fr
We've set up our columns to have two columns each of
我们设置了两列布局
them taking up half of the available space left,
每列各占据一半的剩余空间
and we've set up our rows to be as many rows as we need to fit
行数可以根据我们内容任意增加
each element in the two columns between 50 pixels and 135 pixels.
只不过都需要在 50 像素到 135 像素之间
So what would happen if we added another column?
如果我们多添加一列会发生什么 ？
We can see that it adjusts perfectly.
可以看到它们会自动调整
So now we have three columns and two rows.
现在我们有了 3 列 和 两行
We could continue doing this or we could try using repeat,
我们可以继续手动添加 或是使用 repeat 函数
let's say 4, 1fr.
比如 (4, 1fr)
Now we can see that it has gone into four columns and the boxes adjust accordingly.
现在它变成了 4 列 所有的元素依然会自动调整位置
This is an example of how you can use minmax with grid-auto-rows and
这就是关于 grid-auto-rows minmax 以及
repeat with columns to create fancy auto magic grids.
repeat函数结合起来使用的一个例子了
Good luck doing this on your own. I believe in you.
亲自动手尝试一下吧 祝你好运